[gun fires three times]
- [tires squeal]
- [engine revs]
In an attempt to return to normalcy,
Las Encinas is reopening its classrooms.
The school board has sent us
an official communiqué confirming that.
[Rocío] You don't think
this could happen here.
[reporter] Two weeks later, we still
don't have information on the shooting.
Thankfully, there were no injuries.
We'll update you as the story develops.
[somber music playing]
My sister got out of there.
Now her life's incredible.
She's happy, fulfilled.
And look at me.
[man] It'll pass.
The bad times never last.
Just like the good.
[Omar] When will the pain go away, Mateo?
I'm thinkin' about going back
on my medication.
I still have some around.
You don't need
to go back on the medication.
- Much less self-medicate, Omar.
- [sighs]
How long will the damn nightmares last?
The panic attacks?
The black fuckin' cloud
hanging over my head?
Unfortunately, you can't run from it.
Only through it.
Stay with it. Feel it all.
Then one day, you'll be on the other side.
["Ferryboat of the Mind"
by Clinic playing]
[indie rock building]
[Virginia] And I can assure you
that Las Encinas is a safe place still.
[María] How can you know for sure?
I mean, I don't understand
why this is even up for debate.
Our children's lives are in danger.
- [Virginia] María, please.
- [María] No.
I think Dídac… should be expelled.
- Mama!
- Nico, we can discuss this later.
Having Mafia heirs at Las Encinas
doesn't reflect very well-
You're conflating him with the Mafia?
Oh don't. It was all over the news.
[Virginia] Sensational headlines.
Clickbait.
And Dídac is just a teenager.
Yeah. Look, whatever your name is,
I don't really care.
- I'm Luis, academic director.
- Oh. I don't care.
What actually matters is they came
because they knew he went here.
So either you kick Dídac out,
or we're pulling our kids
out of the school.
- Did I make myself clear?
- We have no other choice.
- No. We have no other choice.
- [Alfonso] No, María.
[Virginia] Okay, please!
I'd like to ask you all to take two days.
Really think it over. We'll take a vote.
And if anyone wants
to delegate their vote to someone-
Or to these two,
we'll permit you to do so.
[Roberta] Fine. Under one condition.
Until we have your vote,
keep him out of school.
[parents murmuring]
[tense music playing]
[Virginia] Okay. Uh, thank you.
Once you've made a decision,
we'll continue this conversation.
[Nico] Dídac.
[crickets chirping]
[Dídac] It's fuckin' amazing.
How you can fuck up my life
no matter where I go.
- You need to stop!
- Hey. Relax. Calm the hell down.
They're gonna kick me outta school.
Pop's gonna take me back to Jávea.
What the hell are you up to
that'd lead to a shootout?
You're not going anywhere anytime soon.
Answer my question.
If you wanna stay out of this mess,
then stay out of it.
That's fine with me.
But then don't ask any more questions.
- I had made real friends here.
- I told you, you're not leaving.
Trust me, man.
We can't let them do this.
This is a fucked-up situation.
Well, I mean, literal shots were fired.
All right. Let's go.
Everyone back to their seats, please.
[Nico sighs]
[tense music fades slowly]
Nico, would I be able to borrow
those photos of you with Dídac?
I swear I'll give them back to you,
but I think I could use these
to maybe help him stay.
Thanks.
[locker closes, locks]
[Sonia] Nico!
Hey, um, you know, I think
it's really cool you're fighting for him.
He's my best friend.
The ones who'll do anything
for their friends
are the ones you wanna keep around.
[cell phones chime]
CHECK OUT THE SLUTTY NEW GIRL.
Wait, what's happening?
Did all our phones go off
at the same time?
[students murmuring]
It's explicit content,
and they're calling the girl a slut.
It's probably a fake account.
Looks like someone leaked a sex tape.
Hey, don't watch it.
If it's leaked, it's invading her privacy.
Well, I know I will. Why the hell not?
Sara, come on. Don't.
[cell phone chimes]
- Are you filming right now?
- [tense music playing]
Filming me turns you on, huh?
- [guy panting in video]
- [girl in video moaning]
- All right. Stop.
- [phone beeps]
Sure took you a while before snatching it.
You were judging me
and snooping simultaneously.
- [tense music building]
- [sighs]
[sighs]
- [Sonia] Hello.
- Hey.
I wanted to say,
them leaking that video was awful.
You must feel like shit.
Not really. I'm good.
I'm not losing any sleep, you know?
Well, shit. If that'd happened to me…
Look, they stole my phone the other day.
Things happen. That's life.
And since there's not much
I can do about it. Next.
By the way, I'm Chloe.
Sonia.
Nice to meet you.
[gentle music playing]
I do appreciate the concern.
[music fades]
["Se la pasa bien" by Faire
playing on stereo]
Too bad this was a pool day, huh?
Relax. We'll be fine here too.
It's the company that matters.
Plans are just a pretext, right? Cheers.
Now these are ice cubes.
Not like they serve overseas.
Spanish ice cubes are just the best.
[man chuckles]
Hmm.
Come on. Try to behave.
When I'm good, I'm so very good.
But when I'm naughty, I'm better.
[chuckles] Well, cheers.
[door opens]
[Chloe] Hi, Mom.
Oh, hey. Hon, do you remember José Luis?
Well, that rings a bell.
[José Luis] She was so little back then.
Well, well. How you've grown.
Well, yeah.
And… I've grown pretty well too.
Why don't you go for a walk?
We have a lot to talk about.
[Chloe] Sure.
Well, been a pleasure, José Luis.
Yeah, for me too.
- Hey.
- [tense music playing]
Eyes over here.
[José Luis scoffs]
[typing on phone]
Psst, psst, psst. Hey.
[whispering] Is my daughter gone?
[José Luis] Mm-hmm.
[rhythmic music playing]
- [mother] What?
- [laughs]
[both laugh]
[groans]
Carmen! That's uncalled for.
Assholes like you make my blood boil.
But I didn't say anything.
- You didn't say it out loud.
- [clicks tongue] You made your point.
[sighs]
Come on. Come here, silly.
[sighs] You wouldn't happen to have a suit
from one of your other lovers, would you?
[Carmen laughs]
If you're not careful,
you might end up eating this skirt.
[chuckles] Well, now.
I'll have to take the taxi home
with a stain.
- See you tomorrow?
- Mm-hmm.
Come on, silly.
We'll talk more tomorrow
about… what brought you to Madrid.
- It's not me, I'm sure.
- Aren't you clever?
Ciao.
- Welcome, welcome!
- [Iván sighs]
- You got it?
- Yeah, I'm good.
[Isa] Okay. I'll leave this over here.
Yeah, that's fine.
- Hey, are you hungry?
- Yeah. We can order something.
Good, 'cause I am starving.
Let's order something yummy. Like pizza.
- I'd love that.
- Mm, okay.
All right.
[group] Surprise!
Hey!
[friends cheer]
[group chuckles]
Thanks, guys.
[birds singing outside]
[Iván] Even though the police
say there's evidence
that points to the burned car being his,
I know it wasn't Patrick.
Yeah, but then he disappeared
with his family.
I mean, it's weird.
I know, but I don't care.
It wasn't him.
- [tense music playing]
- [Iván inhales sharply]
He'd never do that to you.
Iván, I feel… awful.
I am so, so sorry.
Truly.
Sorry for all the pain you've been through
in a… short time.
Be right back.
[tense music building]
[crying softly]
[sniffles]
[music fades slowly]
I'll go see what's up.
[Sara continues crying]
What are you doing?
What the hell are you thinking?
Huh?
Are you gonna confess?
You can't be serious.
You're fucking…
[Sara inhales sharply, sniffles]
I can't do this.
Oh, so you can't do this?
Oh, poor Sara!
You think you're
the only one going through it?
[scoffs]
Do you wanna go to the cops? Let's go.
But I'll confess for you.
- You what?
- I'll tell them I was the one driving.
What are you talking about?
It's about getting
this fucking thing over with,
but I'm not gonna let you ruin your life
or rot in a cell.
I mean, there's no way.
I would rather I go to prison than you.
Or kill myself if I have to.
[ominous music playing]
[Raúl sniffles]
[exhales] Listen to me.
No one has to pay
if we just stick together.
The worst is over now. I promise.
Just trust me.
[kisses]
[gently] Okay? Hey.
Hey.
SCHOOL OF SOCIAL WORK
Okay, for tomorrow, make sure you've read
the origin and theoretical perspective
of the Frankfurt School.
Thank you.
[indistinct chatter]
[professor] Omar.
Someone contacted the school
about a paid internship.
You'd be coordinating
and managing an app to support students
at a school called Las Encinas.
You went to that school, didn't you?
No. I didn't.
Oh, no? Oh.
Well, I thought I read that in-
- Well, I didn't.
- [professor] Well, sorry about the mix-up.
In any case, if you're interested
in the internship, call him.
[sighs] No, thank you.
I'm not interested.
ACADEMIC DIRECTOR
Why are you asking us to do this?
[Luis] Nico's become
the wonderful young man he is today
thanks to his role models at home.
But at this point in his life,
he needs role models who are his age,
that treat him as an equal.
It's natural.
I think that's what Dídac is for Nico.
I mean…
it'd be unfair to have one student pay
'cause of who his family is.
And another lose his friend and role model
'cause of his family's stubbornness.
- [María inhales sharply]
- [Alfonso sighs]
[María exhales deeply]
[sirens wailing]
NO TO SPECULATION
[crowd clamoring]
[people chanting] People without homes!
Homes without people!
[chanting continues indistinctly]
SQUAT HOUSE RIOTS
[reporter] The occupied space,
located in an area of the capital
known as Madrid Río,
is asserting its self-proclaimed status
as a social center.
In fact, the activists responsible…
María.
What?
- Did you see him just now?
- [María] See who?
[reporter] …the activists
on the name, we were told,
like a spider, the center has woven
its own web…
[guy grunts]
- [somber music playing]
- [María gasps]
- [activists clamoring]
- [man screaming]
- [sirens wailing in distance]
- [María] Thank you very much.
Eric!
- Hi, Auntie.
- [María] Hello. [sighs]
- Are you okay?
- [Eric] Mm.
[María] Where are your parents?
[sighs] They don't know I'm here.
What do you mean,
they don't know you're here?
I'll tell them right now.
No, don't. I don't want them to know.
They're not in my life anymore. Period.
Where are you living?
Wherever I can find a place.
How's my cousin Nico?
Great. He's well. He's… very happy.
[Eric sighs]
I'm so proud of him.
[gentle music playing]
[María sighs]
Come on. Let's go.
[music fades slowly]
[Sara] Really?
- [Isa] Don't you remember?
- [Iván] I'll take one.
- Thank you.
- [Nico] Thanks.
[Rocío sighs]
You all right, Sara?
Yes, it's just these kinda things
make me a little intense.
Oh, don't you worry, honey.
We're all very intense here.
[laughs]
- Pizza and music?
- Uh, yes, please.
["Lugar Seguro 3.0" playing]
[catchy Spanish dance music
playing on stereo]
[laughing inaudibly]
- [doorbell rings]
- The pizza guy's already here?
["Lugar Seguro 3.0" continues playing]
[Isa] Hello.
Hello.
Nico invited me.
And I wanted to give Iván a hug.
- Hey, Dídac.
- [Dídac] How are you?
- Good.
- I'm so happy to see you.
Well, head into the living room.
Everyone's there.
- [Dídac] All right.
- See you in a sec.
What?
Do you really think
it's best to keep avoiding him
on his last night
before they take the vote?
Iván, mind your business.
Isa, wait.
Look. I know all too well
what it's like to realize that
you won't be able to spend time
with someone again.
Or do the things you never did together.
And it hurts like hell.
You have no idea.
And you?
How're you doing?
We're really getting on your nerves,
aren't we?
I really appreciate it, but-
If you say the word, give me
three minutes, and I'll kick them out.
[Isa sighs]
Hello.
Hey, bro!
Nico!
[chuckles happily]
Oh! How are you? You stayin' for dinner?
Actually, he's living here.
- He's stayin' here?
- [Alfonso] He is?
And, um… for how long?
Not sure. For a while, probably.
- [Nico] Oh yeah!
- [both laugh]
[María, whispering] Please.
We'll talk later.
[gentle music playing]
[Nico sighs] Dude, I'm telling you,
you must have some major balls
to slug it out with cops
who are armed to the teeth.
Weren't you scared shitless?
[chuckles] We have to fight
if we wanna end injustice, man.
If we don't stand up, the bad guys win.
That's right.
[Nico chuckles]
[Nico] And were you there the whole time?
Didn't you leave?
How could I leave?
I'm the one that runs the show there.
[Nico chuckles] I would've shat myself
in your situation.
"If we don't stand up,
then the bad guys win." [scoffs]
Good guys and bad guys.
Violent and immature.
What were you thinking, bringing him here?
What should I have done?
I couldn't leave him out there.
Well, your brother knows him.
Maybe he knows what he's doing.
Eric is a good kid.
Being with Nico, with us.
A home where he can feel warmth,
love, care…
We could get his life back on track.
- Or it'll derail Nico.
- No, that won't happen.
Because Nico has common sense
and won't get into trouble.
[sighs] Please, Alfonso.
I'm only asking for a few weeks.
To just give it a go,
and we can decide from there.
[Nico] Mom!
I'm taking Eric out for a drink.
Okay, sweetheart.
I wanna spend Dídac's last night with him.
We're meeting at Isadora's.
- Don't come back too late.
- [Nico] Okay.
I'll change, and we can go.
María…
Look, I get it.
I know that Eric is your flesh and blood.
But you should show more grace
to your son's best friend,
who actually is
quite a good influence on him.
["Cuídate" by Valeria Castro playing]
[Patrick on recording] Hey.
I've written a thousand letters
on my phone,
and thought up a thousand speeches
in my head to try and get you back.
But ultimately, this message
is to say goodbye.
I refuse to lose you forever,
even if it is necessary.
Let me live with the hope
that one day we will meet again.
[mournful ballad building]
[Patrick] I'm not asking
for something that was never there.
I'm not asking
for something to be invented.
I just wanna go back
to something we once had.
Something that was real.
But for my wish to be fulfilled,
my only option is to disappear.
Or that's what I'm told.
So, until we see each other again…
I love you.
I love you so much, Iván.
I've always loved you, and I always will.
[doorbell rings]
- [ringing continues]
- [sniffles]
[sighs, grunts]
[groans]
- [guy, outside] Hello?
- [grunts] Yeah?
[guy] Yeah, hi.
Did you, uh, order some pizzas?
- Well, I did. But, um…
- [song fades]
I can't move. I'm in a bit of a situation.
Enter the code
on the control panel and come inside.
- The code is one, nine, nine, seven.
- [control panel beeps]
- [pizza guy] Shit. Are you okay?
- [sighs]
[grunts]
- Hey. Do you want me to take you?
[Iván laughs]
I mean, take you inside, you know?
- Like, move you inside the house.
- [laughs] Okay.
- Help me up?
- Come on. Let's go.
- Let's go. One, two, and three.
- [grunts]
- Oh, thanks. Fuck.
- There you are. You okay?
Oh man. This is quite the house, isn't it?
[sighs]
You're all alone here?
Yep. [chuckles]
I'm sorry. Um, asking that.
I know it's not my business.
It's cool.
Hey, look. Just tell me where
to leave this, and I'll bounce, all right?
Yeah, you can put it there. That's good.
[unzips carrier]
Hey, have you had dinner yet?
If you wanna stay for dinner,
I mean, I ordered a lot of pizza.
- Oh shit. That was way too forward.
- Uh, no. No, it's fine.
Well, I, um…
I mean, I can skip a few orders.
- Sweet. [chuckles]
- [sighs]
So where's your kitchen?
I'll go get us some beers.
- You have some, right?
- Yeah, I have beers. It's in the back.
- [pizza guy] Okay. Sick.
- All the way over there.
[footsteps approaching]
[Raúl] Where are you going?
Let's see. Let me see that.
You can barely see it.
Your stubbornness causes this stuff.
- Hmm?
- I'm going to Isadora's.
Why? We saw Iván already.
I wanna see everyone else.
See how stubborn you are? Huh?
[ominous music playing]
[lock clicks]
[keys jangle]
[ominous music building]
C'mon, let's go.
Let's choose a movie before it gets late.
["Hello Kitty (Remix)"
by OH!DULCEARi and ODD MAMI playing]
[song continues over speakers]
[speaking inaudibly]
- [Sonia] Hello.
- How are you, gorgeous?
Guys, this is Chloe.
I asked her to come along and join us.
What's up?
The security forces
are the arm of a fascist state.
Where our human lives are just pawns.
- Oh my God.
- [ "Coco" by Elena Rose playing]
Hey, are you okay?
[inhales sharply] Yeah,
but I'm gonna head downstairs.
I'm more into twerking
than being lectured.
Anyone coming?
No? Well, all right, then.
Wow. Good thing you invited her to join.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go.
I have things to do, but it's been fun.
Uh, I need a drink.
But they'll serve us up here.
[cell phone vibrates]
COME TO MY SUITE.
Going to the john.
Uh, well, I'm leaving too.
I'm going to…
I'm off. [chuckles softly]
Wow. They all left in a hurry.
Yeah, I know.
Hey, I didn't get a chance to thank you.
For not tearing you a new one
when you toyed with me
in order to get to Ari?
[quietly] Wow.
I'm sorry.
Sounded way less passive-aggressive
in my head.
A good-natured little jab.
[chuckles]
It's thanks for stopping you
and not letting you go in the clinic.
I know.
I just wanted to remind you
that the Nico I knew accepted himself.
Just as he was.
["Lento" by Simona and Six Sex playing]
What?
You're standing here for a reason, right?
Yeah. I've been thinking about
what happened to you.
With the video and all that.
What a dick move.
It wasn't a pleasant experience.
'Cause they stole something private.
Not 'cause of what you see.
Which is just sex, after all.
- Have you seen it?
- Seen what?
The video.
No. No, of course I haven't.
Well, do you want to?
[scoffs] What?
Yeah. Everyone else already has.
Let's give it the importance it deserves.
Less than none.
And let me tell you something.
It's only natural that it got leaked
because it's super hot.
It's your privacy.
Yeah, but I'm the one
who wants to show it to you.
So what do you say?
Come on. Why don't we go
somewhere more discreet?
- [ "Lento" continues playing outside]
- [moaning on video]
Well, do you like it?
Surprised you're so shameless
about showing it to me.
And what about you, watching it?
Come on. Let's not be hypocrites.
I turned you on, didn't I?
Look, this is who I am.
Take me…
or leave me.
Hmm?
Take me?
[both breathing heavily]
[softly] Fuck me.
Thing is… I'm more into
having a beer first
and gettin' to know the other person.
Oh. Getting to know them?
Or having them get to know you?
And discover how wonderful you are
and fall head over heels? Hmm?
You're into being admired, and I'm into…
[softly] …turning you on.
- [both panting]
- [ "Lento" continues playing]
[song ends]
Who cares about
a million-euro inheritance,
when euros can't bring everything
I've lost back to me, you know?
Well, yeah, but you… have this house.
And the money will be able
to help you pay for professional help
to overcome the trauma
you've been through.
Or at least set you up
for a comfortable future.
You know, Iván,
I have no future
and no money to secure it.
I'm stuck dealing with
the present every day.
[sighs] I don't know.
The saying's wrong.
Money may not buy happiness,
but, you know, it can buy
something pretty damn close.
[sighs] Fuck. I'm so sorry.
Here, I was trying to cheer you up,
and I've left you worse than I found you.
- No way. You're good.
- If you want, I'll leave.
No, no, no. Stay. Stay.
Even though you're a stranger,
I feel so comfortable with you. [chuckles]
Yeah, me too.
[tender music playing]
["Swoosh (You Move Too Fast)"
by Dylan Sitts playing in distance]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Roberta screaming, muffled]
That's enough!
You and me are gonna talk.
I don't wanna hear a sound.
I said shut the fuck up.
[somber music playing]
I mean, yeah.
The universe keeps giving us signs that me
and you aren't supposed to be together.
But the thing is, maybe those signs
are telling us that we can overcome
any obstacles
that stand in our way, Isadora.
Because here we are again, together.
Okay.
I mean, ideally, it should be way easier
and blah, blah, blah, blah.
I know how it goes.
- [ "Fear of the Water" by SYML playing]
- Okay, then.
Goodbye, Isadora.
No, wait. Hold up.
♪ Some ancient call ♪
I don't want you leaving like this.
♪ That I've answered before ♪
♪ It lives in my walls ♪
♪ And it's under the floor ♪
♪ If this was meant for me ♪
♪ Why does it hurt so much… ♪
Hold on, there's a slight turn right here.
[both laugh]
Now keep going forward.
A little more.
Here.
♪ Love? ♪
♪ You're dislocated ♪
♪ Don't be like that ♪
♪ And you smile when you dive in ♪
♪ Like you're never coming back ♪
♪ So hold my body ♪
♪ Yeah, hold my breath ♪
♪ See your face when I black out ♪
- ♪ I'm never comin' back ♪
- I feel like dancing.
♪ Fear ♪
♪ Of the water ♪
[Chloe panting]
[moans]
♪ You're dislocated ♪
♪ Don't be like that ♪
♪ And you smile when you dive in ♪
♪ Like you're never comin' back ♪
♪ So hold my body ♪
♪ Yeah, hold my breath ♪
- ♪ See your face when I black out… ♪
- Did I do somethin' wrong?
No, not at all. But I'm…
[sighs, quietly] But I can't do this.
I'm sorry.
♪ Fear ♪
♪ Of the water ♪
[song ends]
[Isa grunts] No, stop.
[sighs]
[breathing shakily]
Tell me what's wrong.
I can't do it. I can't.
I can't. I don't know why.
No. You're just not ready yet.
That's all it is.
[inhales sharply] But I want to.
I really want to.
And I want it to be with you.
Hey. I'm not going anywhere.
[Iván] Sorry about that.
I know
I shouldn't have kissed you earlier.
[sighs] Don't worry.
You're good. There's no need to apologize.
I wanted to do it.
[Iván] Do you have a sec?
I haven't been this comfortable
around someone in a long time.
So I'd like for us to maybe be friends.
Just friends. I mean it.
I promise. [sighs]
Okay. It's cool with me.
Yeah?
- Cool. We're bros.
- [both laugh]
And as your new friend, I'd like to…
to give all the money
that I inherited to you.
Meaning I'd like to help you secure
the future you think
you're never gonna have.
["McFly" by Ca7riel playing]
Hey. Um…
Would you like to have a drink sometime
and chat?
A real conversation.
Not… Not me talking at you.
We can get to know each other.
Yeah, well, we'll see
what we can work out.
Uh, what's your Insta? Or your, uh…
[both panting on phone]
[moaning]
You should try to be more careful
with the videos you record of yourself.
We've seen what can happen.
Sweetheart. So, listen.
Maybe you should get off my back.
I mean, we've only just met,
and you're hella intense and annoying.
[quietly] And I'm the leaker of the video.
- Hmm?
- What the hell?
- [music ends abruptly]
- [Chloe chewing loudly]
Okay, look, Mom.
Haven't you always told me
to look for a rich boyfriend
who will treat me like a queen?
Well, at Las Encinas,
I can get a few of those.
And you'll get one
by carrying on that way? Hmm?
I have the attention
of the whole school now.
And three-quarters of them want me.
Look. If there's anything
you've learned from your mother,
it's to respect yourself.
That, and that we have
a lot more to offer.
- Way more.
- Mm.
Yeah?
Like what, Mom?
What else have we got? Tell me.
[somber music playing]
We're nothing but hollow shells.
That's all they want from us.
That's what we take advantage of.
And I'm not doing a thing
I haven't learned from the best there is.
From Pamela, Paris, Kim…
And from you, Mom.
I learned from you.
You're the best in the game.
[ice cubes rattle]
[José Luis] As much as you insist
and try to convince me
with all the tools in your box,
which are quite a few,
I can't issue you Cruz's pension.
It isn't possible.
Do you think I'm stupid?
Of course you can do it.
You were his lawyer.
It's impossible. Period.
Impossible?
A word thrown around by the foolish.
[scoffs, inhales sharply]
Look, Carmen. I can't and won't do it.
Although I suppose this means
you won't want to see me anymore.
[chuckles] Let me see.
The contract I signed
with your father and Cruz
said that I would receive my pension
under the stipulation
that I would stay away from my child.
Wasn't that written in our deal?
That's right.
Very well.
Then, if there won't be a pension,
there's nothing to stop me
from seeing him.
[suspenseful music playing]
[music grows somber]
Joel.
Joel?
- This came for you.
- [Joel grunts]
[sighs] Fuck.
YOUR FUTURE
YOUR FRIEND, IVÁN
[guy grunts]
[guy groans]
[exhales]
What's that? [sighs]
[sniffles]
[tense music playing]
Just explain it to me.
[Joel] What do I have to explain? Huh?
Dalmar, can we have the room to ourselves?
- Go talk in your own room.
- Come on, man.
[sighs] I'm going out.
Not letting you ruin my day.
[Omar] Well?
[door closes]
Look, um… I don't know
when I first thought about it.
But I applied, and that's it.
[Omar] Without telling me?
Oh, do I have to ask permission
if I wanna be anything more
than just a pizza guy?
[Omar takes a deep breath]
And how you gonna pay for it?
With a scholarship.
A scholarship?
You found a scholarship
and a school and told me nothing?
I didn't in case I didn't get in.
Okay. If you have the money,
go to another school.
- [Joel scoffs] What? Why?
- There's a fuck ton of good schools.
- Don't go to Las Encinas.
- Why do you care if I go there, Omar?
Why would I have to give up
the best school if they want me there?
[Omar sighs]
- [clicks tongue]
- [somber music playing]
[sighs deeply]
So, you studied there.
You've told me about
the state school you went to for a year.
Was that a lie?
[sighs] Well, then.
I hid the fact that I applied,
and you hid that you studied there.
We're even.
I never told you
'cause that place fucked me up.
Hurt me and people I loved.
[Omar sighs]
Joel, don't go there. I'm begging you.
Look. I don't know
what happened to you there.
Or what happened
to those loved ones that you mentioned.
[Omar sighs]
But, fuck. Not everyone who goes
to Las Encinas has a hard time.
So many success stories walk out of there.
[sighs] I think it's unfair of you
to try to deny me
the chance to better myself.
And what if they fuck you up too?
What if they don't?
What if, for the first time in my life,
I have a dream for the future?
Or that place can change you.
[scoffs] Omar.
I… I know who the hell I am.
Okay?
And I promise
that nobody will change me there.
[sighs] Look, I'll go.
And then I'll graduate.
After that, I'll walk out the main gate.
If you love me,
trust me and support me.
[tender music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
Well, welcome.
[Joel sighs]
Thank you.
Want a tour?
That'd be great.
[both chuckle]
- [ "Indigo Skies" by Zola Blood playing]
- [background sounds fade]
♪ Words willed and fall under us ♪
♪ Get burned up in the fire… ♪
[Omar, echoing]
How long will the damn nightmares last?
The panic attacks?
The black fucking cloud
hanging over my head.
[Mateo] Unfortunately,
you can't run from it. Only through it.
Stay with it. Feel it all.
What about shock therapy?
Going back and facing it head-on?
It'd do more harm than good.
- ♪ We lie like stones… ♪
- [Mateo sighs]
Right now you need to protect yourself.
You need to stay away from all that.
♪ …by the tide ♪
[panting]
♪ All this is noise ♪
- ♪ Now it's gettin' away ♪
- [water running]
♪ Puts tears in your eyes ♪
[Omar sighs]
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I've got to go ♪
♪ I think I had too much ♪
♪ A symphony that's gettin' hard to stop ♪
[knocking on door]
- ♪ Indigo skies start to lift me up… ♪
- Good afternoon.
Are you the academic director?
Yeah, that's right.
I'm from the School of Social Work.
I'm a student there.
I'm here about the paid internship
to run an app for the school.
All right. And your name is?
- I'm Omar.
- [Luis] Okay. Have a seat.
♪ A little bit of savagery ♪
♪ It's in all of us ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ I've got to go ♪
♪ I think I had too much ♪
♪ A symphony
That's gettin' hard to stop… ♪
Okay, so what was
the decision of the vote?
Both yours and the others.
♪ Indigo skies start to lift me up… ♪
That… Dídac can stay.
♪ Breathe in the oxygen… ♪
Roberta?
Yeah, same thing. He can stay.
I really hope we're making
a smart decision here.
María, let me reiterate.
As academic director,
I'll be looking after each student.
NIGHTLIFE VENUES
[Luis] I will ensure their safety
and well-being.
RAMOS VICO FAMILY
[Luis] You have my word.
[music slowly building]
TRIPS TO MADRID
[music fades]
[somber music playing]